It can take a lifetime to find true love; she's got 30 days!
The Princess Diaries 2: Royal Engagement is a comedy,
drama, family film directed by Garry Marshall.
Mia Thermopolis is now a college graduate and on her way to
Genovia to take up her duties as princess.
Accompanied by her friend Lilly, Mia continues her 'princess
lessons', like riding horses side-saddle and archery.
But her already complicated life is turned upside down once again when she learns that she is to take the
crown as queen earlier than expected, all while she meets a mysteriously charming young man.
Mia Thermopolis, played by Anne Hathaway.
Queen Clarisse Renaldi, played by Julie Andrews.
Joe, played by Héctor Elizondo.
Viscount Mabrey, played by John Rhys-Davies.
Lilly Moscovitz, played by Heather Matarazzo.
Nicholas Devereaux, played by Chris Pine.
The Princess Diaries 2: Royal Engagement is a 2004 American
romantic comedy film directed by Garry Marshall.
Produced by Walt Disney Pictures, it is the sequel
to 2001's The Princess Diaries.
Unlike the first film, it is not based on any existing book, and has no relation to the second
installment in the book series, The Princess Diaries, Volume II: Princess in the Spotlight.
In the film, Mia Thermopolis learns that before she can succeed her grandmother as
queen of Genovia, she must marry or else relinquish the throne.
Most of the cast returned from the first film, including Anne Hathaway, Julie
Andrews, Héctor Elizondo, Heather Matarazzo, and Larry Miller.
Garry Marshall returned to direct and Debra Martin
Chase and Whitney Houston to produce.
New characters include Viscount Mabrey (John Rhys-Davies), Lord Nicholas Devereaux
(Chris Pine, in his feature film debut), and Andrew Jacoby (Callum Blue).
The film grossed $135.3 million worldwide but received
mixed to unfavorable reviews from critics.
As of 2024, a sequel is in development, with Adele Lim attached as director.
The film explores themes of coronation, marriage, duty, falling in love, calm.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.